Guide to the Karl P. Cohen papers M1798
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Karl P. Cohen papers
1931-2010
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Cohen, Karl P.
M1798
30 Linear Feet (61 boxes: 59 manuscript boxes; 1 record storage box; 1 flat box)
Dr. Karl Paley Cohen was a physicist and advisor involving nuclear energy and reactor development who began his career making scientific advances in uranium production with the Manhattan Project at Columbia University in the 1940s. Working under Harold Urey, Cohen developed the now universal method of centrifugal isotope separation for enriching uranium. While the collection includes many declassified lab notebooks and journals from this time, it largely covers Cohen’s long period of service with General Electric as well as various consultancies, and includes reports, correspondence, notes, and other material related to nuclear electric power generation and its safety, economic viability, public policy and other concerns.
Access to Collection
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given by Karl Cohen to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2010.
Biographical
Karl Paley Cohen (1913-2012) was born in New York City. He studied chemistry at Columbia University from 1929 to 1936, followed by post-doctoral work in Paris (where he met his wife, Marthe-Hermance Cohen). Beginning in 1937 Cohen was research assistant to professor Harold Urey, who had earned the 1934 Nobel Prize in Chemistry for his work on isotopes. As the war escalated, Urey was named director of the Manhattan Project at Columbia, and Cohen was hired as head of the project’s Theoretical Division, with the responsibility for determining processes for U-235 (uranium) isotope separation. Subsequently, Cohen was deeply involved with perfecting the gaseous diffusion and centrifuge techniques for enrichment, and uranium sources and production would be a major focus of his career.
In 1944 Dr. Cohen began working for Standard Oil, primarily studying the economics of the emerging nuclear energy industry. Following this, Cohen was a technical director for H.K. Ferguson's Atomic Energy Division, responsible for the construction of the Brookhaven nuclear reactor. By 1952, Cohen was a founder, vice president and operating manager of Walter Kidde Nuclear Laboratories, a privately-funded research facility formed to commercially develop nuclear power. The lab’s principal contract was with the Atomic Energy Commission for R&D on reactors, and established many industry standards, especially regarding slightly enriched uranium and water moderated reactor concepts.
Cohen’s long association with General Electric began in 1956, at first as a consultant, then as a manager involved with advanced engineering, advanced products, breeder reactor development, and operational planning. In 1973 Cohen was appointed Chief Scientist of G.E.'s commercial nuclear department. After his retirement in 1978, Cohen consulted for companies such as G.E., Boeing, and Exxon, and organizations such as the Institute for Energy Research, Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy and the Electric Power Research Institute. Cohen also continued to be active on committees, at conferences, and in more informal peer review of technology and policy papers. He also taught intermittently at Stanford during this time. Karl Cohen passed away after a long illness in 2012.
Cohen holds several patents in nuclear reactor technology and isotope separation, having developed the now universally-used centrifuge method, and wrote the standard reference text "Isotope Separation" in 1945. He was elected to the National Academy of Engineering in 1967 and served as president of the American Nuclear Society for 1968-1969.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Karl Cohen include reports, papers, articles, notes, memoranda and correspondence, primarily related to nuclear power generation. The collection has been divided into fourteen series. Cohen's own work, with some declassified items dating from the 1930s and 40s, is contained for the most part in Series 1-4, although his student notebooks are in Series 9, and scientific reprints in Series 11. There are also media-specific series here for photographs, slides, and audiovisual material. The subject file series has been arranged alphabetically, and represent companies, organizations, countries, technical processes, and concerns (such as forecasting, economics, proliferation, and safety) which featured heavily in Cohen’s career.
Nuclear energy.; Nuclear reactors; General Electric Company.; Cohen, Karl P.; Cohen, Karl P.; Manhattan Project (U.S.); Urey, Harold Clayton
- 1. Cohen papers, 1939-1992
  Scope and Contents
  Material created and chronologically arranged by Cohen, including scientific papers, lectures, articles, reports, notes, memoranda, correspondence, transcripts, and prepared testimony. Wartime documents were declassified in 1972. Some are copies and appear related to legal research, possibly for patents. 1939-1940 files are all reprints. There are no files for 1990 and 1991. Other work by Cohen can be found throughout the collection.
  - 1939-1940
    - Papers (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Dunning Claim, 1940-1962 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Declassified Reports M-446, M-1340, M-1342 [etc., contains list] (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - ALSOS/DIV IV, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1945-1952
    - Esso [Laboratories, part of Standard Oil] (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - talks, papers, seminar (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - AEC Consulting (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Slightly Enriched Reactors (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1952-1956
    - Investment in Atomic Energy - Prospectus for Development Company, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Brookhaven and AEC Consulting, 1948-1956 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - papers, talks (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1956-1965
    - papers, talks, correspondence, 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Speeches to 1965 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1966-1975
    - papers (Box 9, Folder 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to 1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Speeches (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1976
    - papers (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - JCAE (Joint Committee on Atomic Energy)Testimony, 1976-02 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1977
    - papers (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1978
    - Oregon Paper (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - papers (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - IIASA Drafts (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1979
    - papers (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1980
    - papers (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1981
    - papers (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1982
    - papers (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1983
    - papers (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Urey (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1984
    - papers (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Front End of the Fuel Cycle (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Privatization, 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1985
    - presentation with slides (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1986
    - papers (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Phoenix Forum (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Saratoga Paper (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1987
    - papers (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1988
    - papers (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1989
    - ANS Fuel Cycle (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1992
    - papers (Box 12, Folder 5)
- 2. Cohen writing, 1931-2001
  Miscellaneous work by Cohen, including papers, lectures, and other writing, arranged chronologically.
  - untitled presentation [draft with notes and transparencies] (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "A Modest Proposal" school paper, 1931 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Thesis, 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - MIT Lecture, 1947 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - The Future of Nuclear Energy [draft manuscript of presentation], 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Science Article [Cohen breeder reactors article with notes], 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Berkeley Seminars, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Urey Biography material, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Urey Biography. The War Years 1939-1944 [draft typescript], 1983-03-21 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - quantum mechanics paper, etc. [labeled AIF Phoenix 86] (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Think Pieces 70s-80s [mainstream/popular articles with notes] (Box 22, Folder 3, Folder 4)
  - Techsnabexport notebook, circa 1970s (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Issues Affecting Nuclear Power in the Next Century (BNES "Nuclear Energy" reprint), 2001 (Box 46, Folder 6)
- 3. Cohen patents
  Material related to Cohen's patents, including correspondence, articles, etc.
  - Patents (Box 17, Folder 2, Folder 3)
  - Books and Articles, 1946-1951 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- 4. unclassified/declassified files
  These files (including correspondence, reports, meeting minutes, and journals) had been kept in a safe at the General Electric library prior to release to Cohen, but much of it pre-dates his employment there. Folders were originally organized in two numerical sequences, but contain significant gaps. Some itemized lists are enclosed.
  - lists and miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1.02 Correspondence from AEC, 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1.23 Gas Characteristics - AEC, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 2.56.01 General Correspondence Consultants, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 2.57 Proposals, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 7.16 Mass Flow - Foreign, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 9.01 Correspondence to KPC, 1959-1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 9.02 Correspondence to KPC, 1960-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 9.08 General Calculation Methods - KPC, 1951-1958 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 11.01 Correspondence to Allied, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 11.02 Correspondence from Allied, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 11.53 Allied - Security, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 11.90 Allied - Economics, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 2. Secret, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 5. Chicago Reports, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 6. Washington Reports, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 8. Columbia Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 10. Reactor Physics Planning Group (RPPG), 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 11. RPPG Second Meeting, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 13. RPPG Fourth Meeting, 1951-1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 14. RPPG Fifth Meeting, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 16. KPC Patent, Pre-WKNL, 1950-1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 17. W.O.1492C Reports, 1951-1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 18. Baird Associates Proposal, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 22. Contract W-7405-ENG-50, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 23. Information Meetings [draft report from Oak Ridge] (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 24. OEMsr-412, 1941-1943 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 26. E. Teller - Slightly Enriched Reactor, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 27. WO-1384, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 30. OA-LXXX-729-3A TS-1050, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1002. Legislative, Governmental Control and Commissions - Public Policy (Pre-MacMahon), 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Irving Kaplan S.A.M. Lab notebook (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Columbia lab notebook, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- 5. correspondence, 1978-2000
  Incoming correspondence as well as some outgoing drafts and copies, arranged chronologically. Also includes memoranda and some printed email.
  - 1978 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - 1979 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - 1980 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - 1981 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - 1982 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - 1983 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - 1984 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - 1985 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - 1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1987 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - 1988 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - 1989 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - 1990 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - papers, articles, email and other correspondence [includes Kramish correspondence], 1999-2000 (Box 56, Folder 2, Folder 1)
- 6. people, 1958-1992
  Majority of files assembled by Cohen. See also correspondence series and elsewhere.
  - Bethe, Hans A. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Connolly, Thomas J. [Stanford], 1984-1992 (Box 22, Folder 2, Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Crowley, John H., 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Davis, W. Kenneth [Bechtel], 1958-1979 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Fuhse, Wilmar A., 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Häfele, Wolf, 1972-1980 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Heimann, Fritz F., 1967-1982 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Hurwitz, Henry Jr. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Keck, Dr. Otto, 1980-1988 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Kennedy, William F. [G.E.], 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Komanoff, Charles, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Lewis, W. Bennett, 1962-1974 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Lovins, Amory B. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Marchetti, Cesare, 1978-1986 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Maxey, Margaret N., 1977 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Olander, Donald, 1980-1981 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Perry, Alfred M., 1972-1978 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Phung, Doan L., 1979-1983 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Phung - Safety, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Radkowsky, Alvin, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Richards, Robert B., 1979-1980 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Salaff, Stephen, 1978-1980 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Starr, Chauncey [EPRI], 1970-1992 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Stathakis, George J. [G.E.], 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Teller, Edward, 1963-1980 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Weinberg, Alvin, 1972-1988 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Wolcott, J.R. [NUEXCO] (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Wolcott, J.R. Correspondence re: Privatization, 1984-1985 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Wolfe, Bertram [G.E.], 1976-1989 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Zacharias, Jerrold, 1980-1982 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Zebroski, E.L., 1959-1985 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- 7. conferences, 1974-1987
  Chronologically arranged. Conference material also present elsewhere in collection.
  - Vienna Meeting - English/French/German glossary, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Center for Theoretical Studies, University of Miami, 1977-1982
    Initially known as the International Scientific Forum on an Acceptable World Energy Future, but its name changed with every meeting.
    - Florida, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Miami, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Paper, 1978-11-28 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Other [notes, correspondence] (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - International Scientific Forum on Energy for Developed and Developing Countries. Nice, France, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 6, Box 13)
    - Miami - Texts, 1978-1981 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Miami 1980, 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Miami Billings (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Miami, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - International Scientific Forum on Geopolitics of Energy (Fouth in a Series) - University of Miami. Program and Correspondence, 1980-11 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - AIF International Conference on the Nuclear Fuel Cycle. Stockholm, Sweden, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - AIF International Conference on Uranium Enrichment. New York, New York, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - International Conference on Nuclear Power and its Fuel Cycle. Salzburg, Austria, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - AIF Fuel Cycle Forum. Kansas City, Kansas, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - ANS Symposium. Las Vegas, Nevada, 1978
    - American Nuclear Society Symposium. Las Vegas, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Uranium Resouces - An International Assessment. Proceedings of ANS/DOE Topical Symposium, 1978-09 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - AIF International Conference on Uranium Enrichment. New Orleans, Louisiana, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - AIF Fuel Cycle Forum. Atlanta, Georgia, 1984
    - brochures, reports, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Conference Papers, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - AIF Fuel Cycle Conference. Scottsdale, Arizona, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - AIF "Enrichment Marketplace in the 1990's" Conference, San Francisco, California, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- 8. subject files
  The subject file series was created to group all of Cohen's files related to his consultancies, special projects, technical processes and developments, and overall concerns within the nuclear power industry (such as proliferation). Most files related to his work at G.E. are contained here.
  - 1. American Nuclear Society (ANS)
    American Nuclear Society
    - Policy Statements, 1979-1987 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - directories, 1973, 1999 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - China trip, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 5, Folder 4)
    - China trip - Photographs and Slides, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - 2. Atomic Industrial Forum, Inc. (AIF)
    Atomic Industrial Forum
    - AIF Committee, 1977-1982 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - AIF Technical Papers, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 2, Folder 1)
    - AIF Committee 87 [reports, articles], 1982-1992 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - AIF Committee [Subcommittee on Enrichment], 1983-1985 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - AIF Committee [Subcommittee on Enrichment] - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - 3. Boeing
    Cohen consulted for Boeing on gas centrifuge enrichment and privatization.
    - Boeing, 1975-1990 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Contract/Billing, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - 4. breeder reactors
    - Breeder APO (Advanced Products Operation) Plans - KC (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Breeder APO [Clinch River Breeder, etc.] (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Breeders - FRG (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Breeders - France (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - FBR (Fast Breeder Reactor) Safety (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - FBR - External Review - AEC, 1965-1979 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - FBR Internal Review, 1968-1971 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - FBR Cost Benefit Analysis, 1972-1978 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Breeder Papers - G.E., 1971-1973 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Clinch River Breeder Reactor (CRBR), 1978-1982 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - 5. British Nuclear Fuels Ltd. (BNFL) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 6. Canada
    - Candu (Canadian Deuterium Uranium Reactors) Cohen Calculations, etc., 1958-1979 (Box 31, Folder 7, Folder 6)
    - Candus - Philip Sporn, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Cost Experience - Canada, 1980-1985 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - 7. Carbon Dioxide articles (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 8. Chernobyl, 1986-1988 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 9. Civex Method
    - reports, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Assignment, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 10. Commonwealth Edison Project reunion, 1988 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - 11. Deuterium Oxide [Heavy Water]- KPC Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - 12. economics
    - Economics 78, 1966-1984 (Box 24, Folder 3, Folder 4)
    - Economics - Recent, 1980-1983 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - 13. Electric Power Research Institute (ERPI)
    Electric Power Research Institute
    - reports, slides, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Multicomponent Cascades, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Multicomponents - EPRI Paper, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Contract, 1978-1982 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Contract, Billings, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - 14. energy, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 15. Exxon
    Exxon Corporation
    - Laser, 1969-1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Separation Demand, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Pre-Contract Correspondence, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Security, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Enrichment/Proliferation, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Organization, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - DOE Contract Negotiation, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Contract, 1978-1980 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Billings, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - 16. Fast Flux Clad Damage, 1973-1980 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - 17. forecasting
    - Forecasts (non-G.E.), 1971-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Nuclear Forecasts - Recent "Official", 1974-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Energy Forecasts [includes Cohen AEIC Talk], 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 18. France (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 19. Freeman Consulting Inc./SWUCO
    - Freeman, 1983-1987 (Box 23, Folder 3, Folder 2)
    - SWUCO Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Billing (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - 20. fuel cycle
    - Fuel Cycle reports, etc., 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Fuel Cycle - Uranium History (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fuel Cycles + Foreign, 1980-1985 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - 21. fusion, 1968-1990 (Box 35, Folder 2, Folder 3)
  - 22. General Electric Company (G.E.), 1953-1982
    General Electric Company.
    - G.E. Policy, BWR [many Cohen papers], 1953-1972 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Advanced Development Programs in BWR Technology - AEC Proposal, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Program for the Attainment of Competitive Nuclear Power / Zebroski, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Electric Utility Executives Conference. Woodside, California, 1958-09 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Report of Study Team on Nuclear Technology, 1959-08 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Saratoga R+D Facility Sketch (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - G.E. reports, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - G.E. Policy, Fast Breeders, 1968-1974 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - G.E. Policy, Recent, 1971-1977 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Electricity Consumption to the Year 2000 / Crooks, 1972-07 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Overview [Centrifuge?], 1973 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Fairfield, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Operation Sunrise: Program for the Attainment of Competitive Nuclear Power reprint [dedicated to KPC, signed by G.E. staff], 1978-02 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Simulator [G.E. LMFB Program], 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Reed Study, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 23. G.E. Consulting
    - Vienna, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Purchase Orders [payment receipts], 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Sunnyvale, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Billings, 1978-1982 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - G.E. Future, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - G.E. Advanced Engineering Team (AET) NEBG Design Reviews - Improved Plant Definition/Feasability Study Vol.1&2, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 5, Folder 4, Box 39, Folder 1)
    - [BWR6] Design Review 79 [G.E. Product & Quality Assurance Operation. KCP Consultant], 1978-1980 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Design Reviews, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Corporate Research and Development, 1979-1980 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Contract, 1980-1981 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Zimmer, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Assignments- PRISM, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - SP-100 Safety Advisory Board, 1986-1990 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - SP-100 program Contract/Billing (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - 24. Heritage Foundation. The Resourceful Earth: A Response to Global 2000. "Nuclear Power" chapter by Cohen, 1982-1983
    See also 1983-1984 correspondence.
    - Paper (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Data (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - The Future of Nuclear Power: A Projection - AAAS Detroit, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - 25. High Temperature Reactors (HTRs), 1972-1978 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 26. Institute for Energy Analysis (IEA)
    Institute for Energy Analysis
    - reports, notes, correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Institute for Energy Analysis, Oak Ridge, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - IEA reports, 1980-1986 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - 27. International Energy Systems, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 28. International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis [IIASA]
    International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis
    - International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis [labeled USCEA 87], 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - IIASA Papers, 1976-1979 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - 29. isotope separation
    - Other Methods, 1951-1992 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Lasers, 1973-1981 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Developments in Isotope Separation reports, 1981-1984 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - CRISLA (Condensation Repression by Isotope Selective Laser Activation), 1984-1990 (Box 27, Folder 1, Box 26, Folder 3, Folder 2)
  - 30. Light Water Reactor (LWR) History, 1976-1982 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - 31. NUEXCO, 1987-1996
    Monthly reports, annual reviews, etc. from this uranium market consulting and brokerage firm.
    - Contract, 1983-1984 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - NUEXCO/SWUCO reports [misc.] (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - reports, January-December, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - reports, January-December, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - reports, January-June, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - reports, July-December, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - reports, January-June, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - reports, July-December, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - reports, January-June, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - reports, July-December, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - reports, January-June, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 2)